Amy Littlefield-Bousamra

11100 E Meadow View Drive Suttons Bay, MI 49682 Cell: 231-357-4687 Email: amybousamra@live.com

Summary:

I am a creative professional with a diverse skill set and a strong work ethic. Experienced with all the stages of the web development cycle. I have worked with numerous coding, programming languages, graphic art programs, and other multi-media tools (video, animation, graphs for data, PowerPoint, etc.) in order to complete web projects. I also have maintained websites (content management systems), performed web analytics, and implemented SEO tactics. I enjoy working collaboratively with others as well as independently in order tackle projects and meet deadlines.

Key Web Skills:

- HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, SQL, Frameworks/Bootstrap,
- Word Press Development, SASS/LESS, Grunt/Gulp
- Experience with version control: Git/Git Hub, Bit bucket etc.
- Experience using drop-box and video/web conferencing tools
- Interactive design using CSS, SVG, web animation, audio and video
- Responsive design techniques to accommodate mobile to web screen sizes utilizing grid systems, mathematics
- Create mockups, style tiles, wireframes and prototypes, Implement design theory, color and typography
- Graphic design (Illustrator) and photography (Photoshop) for creating logos, banners, buttons, fabric design and other forms of multi-media art
- Search Engine Optimization. Experience with SEO tools such as, Screaming Frog, Moz, Semrush, Google keyword and analytics etc.
- Teacher/Instructional experience in providing step-by-step instructions. K-8 elementary education certified. Also taught computers and theater arts.
- Customer Service Experience Maintained client relations, frequent communication, emails, and experience writing newsletters.

Education:

Full Sail University Orlando, FL BS Web Development and Design (May 2015)

Rio Salado Community College Tempe, AZ Teacher Certification Post-Baccalaureate Education Program

California State University- Arcata, CA Master of Arts in Production/Directing (2000-2001)

City College of New York, New York City, NY Bachelor of Fine Arts in Theater (1992-1996)

Interlochen Arts Academy, Interlochen, MI (Class of 1990 – HS Diploma)

Awards/Honors:

Advanced Achievement Award – Full Sail University – May 2015 Web Design & Development Degree Program Full Sail University Orlando, FL

Course Director's Award for the following courses - 2015:

Programming for Web Applications II
Web Standards Project
Psychology of Play
History of Visual Communications
Intellectual Property and Law
Full Sail University Orlando, FL

Winning Blog Post - 2013:

Fundamentals of Physics – "Robotics and the World of Bugs" View link: https://fundamentalsofphysics.wordpress.com/page/2/

Golden Key Honors Society, graduated magna cum laude City College of New York City, NY

Web Experience:

Freelance - Web Designer/Web Developer

Created websites, logo design for local businesses

- Worked directly with clients to establish project scope, interaction guidelines, and project time lines
- Developed code, video, photos, graphic images and effects to achieve design goals.
- Performed routine updates, upgrades and overall maintenance of website
- Ensured accuracy of website content by thoroughly editing and cross-checking, Implemented SEO tactics and Web Analytics
- Scheduled launch meetings and instructional meetings for CMS if needed or maintained CMS, implemented social media sites,
 Facebook, yelp etc. Local example of website created: http://www.northcountrygrillandpub.com/

Web Designer & Graphic Artist (extra income-hobby)

Creating websites, logos and fabric design

 Fabric design website to display my prints – for sale on Spoonflower.com

http://amyfrancesdesigns.wixsite.com/amyfrancesdesigns

Teaching Experience:

Instructional Assistant: ELL, Intervention (Math and Reading), Indian Ed., substitute teacher

Traverse City Area Public Schools (2018 - Old Mission Peninsula School) 412 Webster Street

Traverse City, MI 49686

 Taught small group math and reading K-5 (ELL, Intervention and Indian Education)

Supervisor: Beth Still Email: stillbe@tcaps.net

TCAPS Human Resources: 231-933-1716

Special Education - Teacher Assistant (2016-2017)

Traverse City Area Public Schools – East Middle School

412 Webster Street

Traverse City, MI 49686

- Assisted special education teacher in middle school classroom
- Provided and supplemented instruction as needed

Supervisors: Colleen Smith/Principal - Email: smithco@tcaps.net

Erin Ryan - Asst. Principal Spec. Ed 231-933-3577

Phone: 231-933-7300

TCAPS Human Resources: 231-933-1716

Computer Teacher/Spring Show coordinator, Preschool Teacher

(Advanced Kindergarten Curriculum Program) (2011-2012)

Rancho Solano Private Schools

1305 S. Gilbert Road

Gilbert, AZ 85296

- When teaching computers collaborated with others teachers to facilitate technology lessons that would also enhance classroom-learning goals while introducing new technology.
- Planned and implemented kindergarten curriculum to meet state standards.
- Taught units in reading, phonics grammar, math, science, spelling, and computers.
- Guided student's learning by creating centers. These 'centers' were designed to enhance concepts, skills, themes or topics being taught in class.
- In 2006-07: co-directed and choreographed spring musical show for grades Pre-K through 8th grade.

Fourth Grade Teacher (2007-2008)

Leading Edge Academy 4815 W. Hunt Highway

Queen Creek, AZ 85242

- Developed lessons and instructed fourth grade curriculum to meet state standards.
- Taught units in reading, grammar, math, science, spelling (applied Spalding Methods), character education and geography.
- Maintained parent communication through consistent communication and weekly newsletter.
- Assessed student progress and adjusted instructional methods

Principal, Laura Newcomb <u>mrslauranewcomb@yahoo.com</u>

Phone: 480-655-6787 Fax: 480-655-6788

Drama Teacher/Director of Theater/Musical Productions (2002-2005)

Quest Academy 500 N. Benton Palatine, IL 60067

- Designed elementary and secondary theater/acting courses and objectives per grade level.
- Directed musicals and staged productions (Moliere, Shakespeare etc.)
- Encouraged students to reflect/analyze human behaviors; personality types and life situations within the context of drama
- Incorporated activities to increase confidence in public presentations.
- Promoted teamwork and problem-solving activities to accomplish common goals in a given improvisation or scene.
- Taught theater history and worked with teachers to create crosscurricular units for learning enrichment. For example, a play where each child wrote and performed a monologue as an early explorer from North America.

Head of School: Marilyn Wallace

Middle School Director Barbara Woodman Phone: 847-202-8035 Fax: 847-202-8085

www.questacademy.org